Grace Brigham

Seattle, WA • nbrigham@uw.edu • linkedin.com/in/natalie-grace-brigham/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Rising graduate of University of Washington's joint BS/MS in computer science program with a passion for the intersection of technology and social impact. Recipient of UW's 2023 Husky 100 award. Experience with software engineering, from Microsoft and co-founded student start-up, as well as sociotechnical work.

EDUCATION

MS, Computer Science

University of Washington, Seattle

BS. Computer Science

University of Washington, Seattle

- GPA: 3.95

- Awards: Husky 100, CSE Excellence Scholarship

- Programs: Interdisciplinary Honors, Lavin Entrepreneurship

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Intern Microsoft. Redmond

06/2023 - Current

Expected Graduation: 6/2024

Expected Graduation: 12/2023

- Team: Responsible Al Tooling, Azure Machine Learning
 - Developed local explainability and interpretability mechanisms for Azure ML Studio
 - Contributed to open source repositories

Undergraduate Researcher

04/2023 - Current

UW Security & Privacy Lab, Seattle

- Studying how to measure and mitigate negative externalities of new technologies
- Leading the creation and development of a research project for understanding people's conceptualization of consent in Deepfakes

Co-Founder, Developer

11/2021 - 06/2023

Mezzo, Seattle

- Built a cross-platform app that helps users make mutually convenient plans for meetups
- Led development of MVP, which is in beta testing
- UW Dempsey Business Plan Competition finalists 2022 and 2023
- DubHacks Next incubator graduate
- Featured in Geekwire and UW's The Daily

Software Engineering Intern Microsoft, Redmond

06/2022 - 09/2022

- Team: Digital Employee Experience, Experiences & Devices
 - Created an administrator portal within an HR application
 - Completed design, development, and testing
 - Implemented full stack changes and additions
 - Deployed the feature to production
- Participated in cloud computing bootcamps

Mentor & Program Lead

01/2021 - 06/2022

- **UW Changemakers in Computing, Seattle**
 - Led summer program for high schoolers with underrepresented identities in tech
 - Developed coding and sociotechnical lessons from scratch
 - Hired and trained a new cohort of mentors

SKILLS

Java | Python | React & React Native | JavaScript | PyTorch | C | C++ | SQL | HTML & CSS | Databases Networking Basics | Responsible Technology | Mentorship | Leadership | Teamwork

VOLUNTEER WORK

Mentor 12/2020 – 06/2021

Society of Women Engineers, Seattle

Mentored high school girls who were interested in STEM, helping them explore career paths, prepare for the transition to college, and navigating challenges, like imposter syndrome.

Academic Excellence Chair UW Kappa Delta, Seattle

12/2020 - 06/2021

Created a resource hub for course and career exploration, preparation, and support. Oversaw and managed chapter academic performance.